<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="tts_text_1" formatted="false">
    <![CDATA[
노무현 전 대통령이 한국인이 가장 좋아하는 대통령으로 꼽혔다. 만년 1위였던 박정희 전 대통령을 제친 셈이다.
한국갤럽은 지난해 10월 2~29일 전국 만 13세 이상 남녀 1700명을 대상으로 가장 좋아하는 대통령을 조사한 결과 노 전 대통령이 32%로 1위를 차지했다고 13일 밝혔다. 박 전 대통령은 28%로 2위였고, 16%를 얻은 김대중 전 대통령이 3위였다. 이어 박근혜 대통령 5%, 이명박 전 대통령 3%, 전두환 전 대통령 1.9%, 김영삼 전 대통령 1.6%, 노태우·이승만 전 대통령 0.8% 순이었다.
연령별로 보면 노 전 대통령은 40대 이하에서 모두 박 전 대통령보다 인기가 좋았다. 박 전 대통령은 50대 이상에서 여전히 1위였다.
노 전 대통령은 전 지역에서 30% 안팎의 지지를 받았다.
가장 좋아하는 정치인 조사에서는 새정치민주연합 안철수 의원이 9%로 1위를 기록했다. 이어 새정치연합 문재인 대표 8%, 박 대통령 7%, 노무현 전 대통령 4%, 새누리당 김무성 대표 3%, 박원순 서울시장 2.4% 등의 순이었다.
이번 조사는 면접 조사원 인터뷰 방식으로 실시됐으며, 95% 신뢰수준에 표본오차 ±2.4%포인트다.
김영석 기자 yskim@kmib.co.kr
GoodNews paper ⓒ 국민일보(www.kmib.co.kr), 무단전재 및 재배포금지
    ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="tts_text_2" formatted="false">
    <![CDATA[
The parents of the U.S. Ambassador to Korea say the man who attacked their son on Thursday wanted to kill him.

They made the allegation in an interview with The Cincinnati Enquirer, a regional daily paper in Ohio.

“Mark was of the mindset that this was a bona fide attempt on his life,” Jim Lippert, the father of ambassador Mark Lippert, was quoted as saying.

“He was going for the neck or the jugular.”

They told local media they had spoken to their son on the phone the day of the attack.
“There were also some lacerations on Mark’s upper-left extremities that were causing some loss of movement in his ring and little finger,” the father said.

Despite about 80 stitches, the U.S. envoy told his parents that there would not be any permanent impairment to his face.

Lippert’s parents said that they “were out getting pizza” when they received a call from Robyn Lippert, the ambassador’s wife.

“I could just see and tell by the tone of the dialogue that this was serious,” said the father.

“Robyn was on her way to the hospital after the attack, but said that Mark was OK and had just spoken to her on the phone.”

The parents headed home soon after the phone call, only to find television news crews reporting the attack.

The father said his son had told them that one of the reasons it had spread so quickly was because of heavy news coverage in South Korea.

“Our settling event was that phone call,” the father explained. “It’s like playing cards. You play the hand you’re dealt and you react to it.”
     ]]>
     </string>


</resources>
